## Q84 Liu

emn1over12@gmail.com | Latest CV at github.com/quinnliu/CV

# **Job Interest**

Looking for a full-time remote full stack developer position using Python, artificial narrow intelligence, machine learning, image processing, range of databases(MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, etc.) & message queues(RabbitMQ, etc.).

## **FUN TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

infinity2o.com (http://infinity2o.com)(coming soon) | Dec. 2017 - Present

Built using AWS, Docker, MySQL, Node.js Loopback RESTful API, & Redux/React.js.

Open Source Artificial General Intelligence(AGI) Research (https://github.com/WalnutiQ/wAlnut) | 2011 - 2015, 2017

College Level CS & Math education at <a href="mailto:youtube.com/quinnliuvideos">youtube.com/quinnliuvideos</a> (https://www.youtube.com/user/quinnliuvideos) | 2013 - 2015, 2017

Machine Learning, Computational Neuroscience, & Robotics | 2013, 2017

- Coded neural networks, linear, & logistic regression in Matlab at <u>quinnliu/MachineLearning (https://github.com/quinnliu/MachineLearning)</u> for prediction & MNIST digit recognition.
- Neuron modeling in Matlab at <u>quinnliu/ComputationalNeuroscience</u> (https://github.com/quinnliu/ComputationalNeuroscience).
- Simulated <u>7 DOF forward kinematics robotic arm</u>
   (<a href="https://github.com/Hunter690/catkin\_ws">https://github.com/Hunter690/catkin\_ws</a>) in ROS & Python to learn precision movement to end effector.

iOS app to allow anyone to listen to music at the exact same time as someone else | Early 2017

- <u>Video demo (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WXTufUtmZYg)</u> of full stack iOS app using React Native, Redux, Node.js,
  - & websocket server.
  - <u>Client code (https://github.com/Laybium/laybium)</u> & server code (https://github.com/Laybium/laybium\_server).
- Apple App Store link (https://appsto.re/us/zQZYfb.i). App is no longer maintained because I don't want to pay AWS fees.

<u>Technical Drawings (https://github.com/quinnliu/CV/blob/master/portfolio/artwork.md)</u> | 2009 - 2012

## **SELF EDUCATION**

MOOCS from Stanford, Columbia Uni., etc. | 2013 - Present

• Courses at <a href="mailto:courses-at-courses-course-courses

Full time student at Classical Art Studio <u>barnstonestudios.com</u> | Summer 2010 & Summer 2011

 Worked 100+ hours/week for 10 weeks each summer to learn classical drawing, design, & oil painting techniques including gold section & fletcher color system to produce visual portfolio (https://github.com/quinnliu/CV/blob/master/portfolio/artwork.md).

## **JOB EXPERIENCE**

Part Time Volunteer at <a href="http://hackny.org/a/">hackny.org/a/</a>) | Aug. 2017 - Present

• Help with accounting using quickbooks & review of hackNY applications.

After AppNexus projects finished left to work as remote coding tutor & travel | Sept. 2016 - Aug. 2017

- Private coding tutor teaching D3.js, Redux/React.js, & Python.
- Lived in Berlin, Prague, Copenhagen, Virginia, & Texas.

Full time Business systems developer at <a href="https://www.appnexus.com/">AppNexus (http://www.appnexus.com/</a>) | Summer 2015 - Sept. 2016

- From provided UI sketches co-developed with a senior software engineer 7 screens that used a
  - **RESTful API**, Redux/React.js to allow contracts with clients to be created, edited, cloned, & deleted.
- Planned out & delivered a 1 month project to create new reports using **RESTful APIs** & a **PHP UI codebase**.

Business systems intern at AppNexus &  $\frac{\text{hackNY Fellow (http://hackny.org/a/)}}{2014}$  | Summer 2014

• Synchronized data across an internally built web app called Console and Salesforce.com using technologies including RabbitMQ, Storm, PostgreSQL, Gradle, Spock, JIRA, & Groovy ready for production.

TA for my favorite CS course at Virginia Tech Software Design & Data Structures | Spring 2014

• Taught 4 hour labs/week & held office hours on android development & Java.

Full time researcher at Vision Lab at John Hopkins University Clark Hall | Summer 2013

- Optimized code for random walk image segmentation for iOS app iMixPics.
   Paper (./portfolio/random walker image segmentation on iOS devices.pdf) & Poster (./portfolio/Poster iMixPics2.jpg)
- Participated in a variety of biomedical research workshops through Computational Sensing & Robotics REU (http://lcsr.jhu.edu/reu/).

Part time researcher at Vision Neuroscience Lab at Virginia Tech Williams Hall | Fall 2012

• Interdisciplinary research with neuroscientist Dr.Cate on models of spatial

learning in visual pathway of human brain with <u>Poster</u> (./portfolio/Scieneering Poster (5MB).jpg).

Dishwasher at Virginia Tech West End | Fall 2012 & Spring 2013

## FORMAL EDUCATION

Virginia Tech Computer Science Major [GPA: 3.59] | 2011-15

- Courses at Virginia Tech(43) (./portfolio/courses\_taken.md)
- Last semester GPA dropped < 3.0 to pursue startup idea

#### COMMUNITIES

#### hackNY Fellow (http://hackny.org/a/) | Summer 2014

• Lived together with 25 other developers in the program & had a lecture series with founders of top NYC based tech companies including Joel Spolsky (Trello & stackoverflow), Jonah Peretti(HuffPo & Buzzfeed), Fred Wilson(USV), Zach Sims(codecademy), Ryan Bubinski(codecademy), etc. to learn the ins & outs of starting & leading a startup.

#### Co-founded Visual Art Club at Virginia Tech | 2011 - 2013

- Taught 20+ members through 2 hour/week workshops about the classical visual arts. Started the club with 2 friends also passionate about visual arts.
- Members with competence in other areas were also given the opportunity to present.

The Recurse Center (https://www.recurse.com/) dropout | Summer 2015

# SMALLER FUN TECHNICAL PROJECTS

- \* = Code is a school project & therefore not shown but happy to share if requested.
- Git
- Cheat sheet at <u>quinnliu/GitCommands</u>
   (https://github.com/quinnliu/GitCommands).
- Java
- Android maze solver app & minesweeper app.
- Earthquake watcher service\* using public earthquake API.
- Memory manager\* & Buffer pool\*.
- C
- <u>Buffer Bomb (https://github.com/quinnliu/bufferBomb)</u>, MIPS assembler, *Extendable shell*, Thread pool, & *Malloc*.
- Web development
  - Amazon EC2, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, & Heroku product kickstarter\*.
  - Google App Engine in Python\*.
- Finished Jersey City Triathlon 2016 with single gear bike.